Luis Sánchez

Software Engineer

Profile

As a Software Engineer, I offer over 10 years of experience successfully completing simultaneous projects. I am enthusiastic about developing forward-thinking solutions to tomorrow's productivity problems and have a resourceful and adaptable approach to challenges. I am a decisive leader and reliable team builder, with a results-focused and driven approach.

Employment History

Software Engineer at Uber. Santiago, Chile

May 2023 - December 2023

- Fraud prevention team.
- Create new verification flows, features and tools for stakeholders and operators for evaluating users.
- Monitoring fraud logs to ensure we are not having any outrage.
- Transform business requirements and strategies to software engineer solutions to be one step ahead of fraudsters.

Backend Engineer at Cornershop by Uber. Santiago, Chile

October 2020 - May 2023

- I am part of the team responsible for managing fraud prevention.
- Developing solutions with the most used payment service providers in the market: Stripe, Adyen, PayPal, CyberSource and Apple Pay.
- Use of Python and Django.
- Monitoring using the latest technologies.
- Transforming business requirements into digital solutions.

Software Engineer (Sr) at In Motion. Santiago, Chile

April 2012 — October 2020

- Use of .NET 4.7, C#, MVC, EF6 and Core, ASP.NET Identity.
- API V3 Google Maps.
- Use of CSS3, HTML5, Bootstrap and JavaScript to improve legacy sites.
- Creation of Docker images using Azure DevOps with CI and CD.
- TDD, Unit tests with Xunit and FluentAssertions.
- WWF, WPF and WCF.

Education

Bachelor's Degree in Informatics Engineering Universidad Católica Andrés Bello, Caracas, Venezuela

September 2003 — October 2009

■ Courses

Prompt Engineer, DeepLearning.ai

May 2023

ScrumManager, Expert level, ScrumManager.org

June 2015 — June 2015

TS: Microsoft .NET Framework - Application Development Foundation. Microsoft License 9023486, Microsoft

March 2012 — March 2012

Details

Simón Bolívar 2580, dpto 213 Ñuñoa, Santiago, 7750000, Chile +56 9 6432 9625

luis.sanchezm86@gmail.com

Links

Twitter

LinkedIn

Stackoverflow

GitHub

Skills

Python, Javascript, .Net

Django, MVC

AWS: S3, Git, CI

Microservices Architecture

Teamwork and Leadership

PL/SQL and T-SQL

Docker, Datadog, Sentry, New Relic

Languages

Spanish

English

Hobbies

Cooking, Running, Tennis, Piano, Gaming.